# Benjamin Lopez

### Lead Software Engineer • Technical Architect

Montreal, Canada benswengineer@outlook.com 5146049239

#### **Profile**

Lead software engineer / Architect with eleven years of experience in full-stack and cloud-based application development (Microsoft Azure). Hands on software architecture, software design, agile methodologies and coaching developers. Looking forward to keep growing, learning and sharing within a team by designing, planning, implementing testing and monitoring applications using modern software architectural patterns that better fit business requirements.

# **Employment History**

Mar 2022 — Present

### Senior Software Developer at Petal

Montréal

Working on maintaining, improving and implementing features for a platform that orchestrates services across Quebec's health care providers. Participating on transforming the company into a world class software services provider and modernizing architecture, patterns and best practices.

| RoR | Elastic Search | MySQL | Redis | Angular | NgRx |

Apr 2021 — Mar 2022

Remote

# Technical Lead | .Net Community Lead at Cognizant Softvision

Focused on coaching and helping developers. Participated in projects for one of the big four accounting companies using Microsoft technologies such as .Net Core and Azure, and top notch front-end technologies.. Hands on architectural, design patterns and agile methodologies like scrum and SAFe.

| Micro-services | Event-Driven | Architecture | DDD |

Jun 2018 — Mar 2021

# Lead Software Engineer at AgileThought

Tampa, Florida - US

Worked on a vast project to transform audit experience for one of the big four accounting companies using cloud-based top notch technologies. As part of the core team I got hands on the foundations of the platform, designing solutions and implementing patterns highly tied to the cloud to enforce the usage of abstract software layers by developers to improve efficiency and maintain architectural integrity.

| .Net Core | Architecture | Azure | Micro-services | Domain-Driven-Design | Design patterns | Redis | Event-Driven-Architecture |

#### **Skills**

В	acl	cen	d I	De	vel	op	me	ent	
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Software Architecture									
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Unit Testing									
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Design Patterns									
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Integration Testing									
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Leadership Skills									
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Communication Skills									
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Agile and Scrum									
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Front-End Development									
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Microsoft Azure									
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
UI/UX									
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
Languages									
Spanish									
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
E	ngl	lisł	1						
•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•	•
F	ren	ıch							

Dec 2015 - Jun 2018

# Senior Software Engineer at Unosquare

Guadalajara, MX

Worked on several projects for an online Bank. Acquired great knowledge on agile methodologies, process improvement and communication skills. Participated on a team focused on delivering value to the business by using tools and technologies we excel at.

| .Net Core | REST | JavaScript | Angular | SQL DB | Scrum | Azure | Process improvement |

Jun 2015 — Dec 2015

## Software Engineer at HCL

Guadalajara, MX

Developed a, from scratch, modern web app to integrate different platforms for mailing, meeting organizers, online chat and more communication capabilities. Made great efforts to enable a high tolerance to failures and implement high resiliency in the system by implementing patterns that provide high interoperability.

| C# .Net | REST | JavaScript | Angular | SQL DB | Design Patterns |

Dec 2014 — Jun 2015

# Software Engineer at PriceTravel

Cancun, MX

Worked on maintaining and adding features to an internal platform of the company. Mostly focused on performance, readability and maintainability of the code, including both front-end and back-end parts.

| C# .Net | JavaScript | jQuery |

Jan 2012 — Dec 2014

Colima, MX

# Software Engineer at Finance and Administration Secretary

Started my journey on web development participating on a large tax administration project. Helped my team to introduce Javascript jQuery and other front-end technologies to the system and assisting junior devs to ramp up.

| C# .Net | Razor | JavaScript | SQL DB | jQuery | Entity Framework | LinQ |

#### Education

Aug 2008 — Jul 2012

Universidad de Colima

Colima, Mexico

Software Engineer